<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Analyst Portfolio on Fatema Arsiwala</title>
    <link>https://fatema-arsi.github.io/Project_Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Analyst Portfolio on Fatema Arsiwala</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fatema-arsi.github.io/Project_Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project I: Correlation Analysis of Stocks</title>
      <link>https://fatema-arsi.github.io/Project_Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>https://fatema-arsi.github.io/Project_Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>With an increase in the penetration of analytics into numerous facest  of our lives, finance is definetely one of the earliest to catch onto this trend. In this project, I have attempted to showcase how data analytics and visualisation techniques can be incorporated in the world of finance.I have used 10 years of historical data from Jan 2011 to Jan 2021 of  Amazon,Google and Tesla stocks from yahoo finance using webreader.Link to this GitHub Repository.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Project II: Finance-Portfolio-Optimization</title>
      <link>https://fatema-arsi.github.io/Project_Portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed,20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>https://fatema-arsi.github.io/Project_Portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>Portfolio optimization is the process of selecting the best portfolio (asset distribution),out of the set of all portfolios being considered, according to some objective. The objective typically maximizes factors such as expected return, and minimizes costs like financial risk.
-Wikipedia. In this project, I have scrapped the stock data using yfinance package in Python. And I have tried to optimize the portfolio for the maximum return with the least amount of risk with the help of a package called pyportfolioopt created by Robert Ansrew Martin. Link to this GitHub Repository. </description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Project III: Sentiment Analysis of Stocks from Financial News </title>
      <link>https://fatema-arsi.github.io/Project_Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>https://fatema-arsi.github.io/Project_Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Instead of having to go through each headline for every stock you are interested in, we can use Python to parse this website data and perform sentiment analysis (i.e. assign a sentiment score) for each headline before averaging it over a period of time. The idea is that the averaged value may give valuable information for the overall sentiment of a stock for a given day.I have used several packages such as ‘BeautifulSoup’ to parse data from FinViz while ‘requests’  to get data and ‘nltk.sentiment.vader’ library  to perform sentiment analysis on the news headlines. Link to GitHub Repository. </description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Project IV:  EDA on Scrapped Data </title>
      <link>https://fatema-arsi.github.io/Project_Portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>https://fatema-arsi.github.io/Project_Portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>Scrapped app description of Dreem, Headspace, sleep cycle, etc. using google-play-scrapper. Delivered insights to understand customer demands better and thus help developers to popularize. To clarifty, the &amp;lsquo;popular&amp;rsquo; in this project means a high number of installation. Performed Exploratory Data Analysis using matplotlib, seaborn and plotly.    Link to GitHub Repository.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Project V: Visualization of MSForms data with Power BI</title>
      <link>https://fatema-arsi.github.io/Project_Portfolio/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>https://fatema-arsi.github.io/Project_Portfolio/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>Gathered the sleep data by building the survey forms in Microsoft Forms.  Click to go to form.
 Set up a blank trigger on Microsoft Flow to get the responses from the surveyed forms and pushed them into a Power BI streaming dataset. Built out a dashboard page with the summary info in it like number of responses, participants &amp;rsquo;s quality of sleep, average hours of sleep taken by them, etc. </description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://fatema-arsi.github.io/Project_Portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>https://fatema-arsi.github.io/Project_Portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>Follow me on these social media platforms.
   Platform URL     Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/fatema-arsiwala-aa1a8718a/   GitHub: https://github.com/Fatema-ARSI   Kaggle: https://www.kaggle.com/fatemaarsi    </description>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
